#Encodergasm Presents
～
（ブルの祈りの歌）
星が落ちたよ ブル
The star fell, Bull.
That is no ordinary star.
（ブル）あれは ただの星ではない
That is the tear of a warrior.
戦士の涙だ
What is a warrior?
戦士って何？
この星のどこかで戦い果てた者
One who has finished his battle somewhere on this planet...
グレートスピリットを
信じられなかった哀れな魂
A pitiful soul that could not believe in the Great Spirit.
（ブルの祈りの歌）
The report from Callisto went directly to Sir Vicious.
（リン）カリストからの通信は
ビシャス様に
直接 入ったもので―
He is requesting a deal for Red-Eye.
レッド･アイの取引を
要求しています
30,000 Woolongs per gram.  A total of 7500 grams.
グラム ３万ウーロン
全部で7500グラムです
Why did he specify you as the dealer?
（マン龍(ロン)）
なぜ お前を指名したのだろうな
He is a Titan veteran.  We were in the same unit.
（ビシャス）
相手はタイタン帰還兵です
私と同じ隊にいた
Why does he rely on you now?
（ピン龍）
なぜ いまさら お前を頼る？
Callisto is undergoing a depression right now.
（ビシャス）
カリストは今 恐慌に陥っている
先が見えず 焦りも出ましょう
If he can't see the future, he is sure to worry.
All the more reason to keep our hands out of that moon.
（ソウ龍）なおのこと
手を付ける意味のない星だ
焦っているのはビシャス
お前では ないのか？
Vicious, are you not the one that is worrying?
独断の意志を持つことは
お前には許されていない
You have no permission to make your own decisions.
万機を乱す者への制裁は
誰であろうと下される
Regardless of who it is, those who go against the Van's will are punished.
私が師父を裏切るとでも？
You believe that I would betray my own mentor?
Mao's case was merely bad luck.
（ソウ龍）マオは不運であった
Lin, you shall go with Vicious.
リン お前は
ビシャスと共に行け
はい
Yes.
Wang Long!
（ソウ龍･ピン龍）マン龍
Callisto is a frigid planet.
カリストは冷えた星だ
Take plenty of winter clothes.
十分な防寒着を用意して行きなさい
To me, no cold climate is worth taking precautions for.
（ビシャス）私には寒さなど
防ぐまでのこともない
It is true that the planet is warmer than your heart.
（マン龍）確かに
お前の心中よりは暖かいだろうな
Your heart is colder than a snake's skin.
蛇の肌より冷たい心だ
Vicious.
ビシャス
A snake cannot eat a dragon.
蛇は龍を食らうことは できない
I will be fine by myself.
（ビシャス）私一人で十分だ
I'll go with you.
（リン）お供します
Remember this.
（ビシャス）覚えておけ
生き延びたければ
時に私を裏切ることも必要だ
If you want to survive, you must betray me at times.
No, never.
（リン）いえ 決して
万機に背くことになります
That would go against the Van's will.
Such old-fashioned thinking makes me nauseous.
古い考えだ　吐き気がする
Those damn corpses!
（ビシャス）しかばねどもが
（リン）あなたを守ります
レッド･ドラゴンの誇りにかけて
I will protect you, for the honor of the Red Dragon.
Honor, huh?
（ビシャス）誇りか？
ならば私が切り捨てるまでだ
Then, it's up to me to slaughter them all!
（スパイク）ぶわっ！ はあはあ
It's hot...
暑い
Where are the others?
他のやつらは？
What a depressing bunch...
陰気なやつらだ
What's with this humidity?
（スパイク）何だよ この湿気は
蒸し暑くて 眠れやしねえや
It's so muggy that I can't sleep!
Oh, it's just a breakdown.
（ジェット）なあに 単なる故障だ
“顔を見ると別れがつらくなるので
会わずに出ていきます”
"It'd be hard for me to do if I saw your faces...
...so I'm leaving without seeing you one last time.  PLEASE don't look for me."
“決して捜さないでください”
That wench...
あの女か
She sucked out all the antifreeze from the radiator.
（ジェット）ラジエーターから
冷却剤を抜いていきやがった
It'll be out for at least half a day.
半日は動けん
Even if she didn't pull this stunt we wouldn't look for her.  Right?
そんなことしなくても
捜さねえさ　なあ？
She emptied out the safe as well.
金庫も空でな
えっ…
7, 8, 9... hello!
（エド）
７ ８ ９ こんにちはっと
Are you really looking for Faye?
（スパイク）おい 本当に
フェイ 捜してんだろうな？
1, 0, 1, 1, goodbye!
（エド）
１ ０ １ １ さようなら
Are you just wasting time?
（スパイク）
無駄なことやってないか？
Is there anything else to do right now?
今 他にすることがあるか？
Ooh!  Boom!
（エド）あ どーん！
（ジェット）いたか？
You found her?!
I wonder who this is...
（エド）この子は誰でしょね？
Let's see... code name...
えっとね
コードネームがジュリア！
Julia!
Where is that coming from?!
どこから発信されてる？
Let's see...
んっとね 近いだから―
Pretty close...
Looks like Blue Crow on Callisto.
カリストのブルークローみたいな…
Where's it going to?
（スパイク）どこに向けてだ？
It got disconnected.
切れちゃった
ああっ？ おい！
Hey!
But...
（エド）でもね
（ジェット）あん？
Actually, there are no girls in Blue Crow.
（エド）ブルークローには
女の子いないの　本当はね…
Honestly...
（ジェット）うーん
Hey, Spike!
おい！ スパイク
Is that it?
もういいの？
ふああああ
うわああああ はああう
（アインの悲鳴）
Hey!
（ジェット）おい！
おい 待てよ スパイク
Hey, wait, Spike!
That's a common woman's name!
あんなのは
よくある女の名前だろうが
What about Faye?
フェイは どうする？
Leave her.
（スパイク）ほっとけよ
This is a lawless area.
（ジェット）この辺は無法地帯だ
A woman surely can't survive wandering about all alone!
女一人でふらふらしてちゃあ
ひとたまりもねえ
Feeling sympathetic?
情が移ったか？
Plenty of sympathy... for the money she ran away with!
情は たっぷりさ
あいつが持ち逃げした金にな
Spike!
（ジェット）スパイク！
I'm gonna go look.
（スパイク）捜しに行く
What?
何っ？
I'm gonna look for my woman.
（スパイク）俺は俺の女をな
あんたは そっちの女を捜せばいい
You can look for that other woman.
You're gonna have nothing to do with this?
（ジェット）
お前は一切 関係なしか？
That's right.  We only go so far.
そうだよな
しょせん そういう関係だ
Even if you come back, there won't be a place for you here.
戻っても お前の居場所はないぜ
Can't do anything about it.
（スパイク）仕方ないさ
I'm sure you're not as lonely now that you have more strange roommates.
（スパイク）妙な同居人が増えた分
あんたも寂しくないだろう
Me?
（ジェット）俺が？
You stayed here just for that reason?
そのために お前がいたのか？
ばかげてるぜ
You're being stupid!
It's been three years since I teamed up with you.
お前と組んで３年だがな
But I never knew you looked at me that way!
今まで そんなふうに
思われていたとは知らなかったよ！
I was under the impression that YOU were the lonely one!
俺はてっきり お前が
寂しいんだとばかり思ってたからな
誤解が解けたな
Well, we got rid of that misunderstanding.
Good riddance!  Now we'll have more money for food!
（ジェット）せいせいしたぜ！
これで食費が浮くってもんだ
I never did understand you, even to the very end!
最後まで お前ってやつが
分からなかったぜ！
I don't understand, either.
俺にも分からねえ
So long!
（ジェット）あばよ！
（サックスの演奏）
I don't know any woman.
女なんか知らん　知るもんか！
Like I would know!
うわさもないか？
Not even a rumor?
I have no luck with 'em!
俺には縁のない生きもんだ
I'd rather be with an armadillo!
アルマジロのほうが まだマシだ
Have you heard of the name Julia?
ジュリアって名前を聞いたことは？
You shoulda said so earlier!
そいつを早く言え
There's one in front of Tony's place every night!
そいつならトニーの店の前に
毎晩 立ってるぜ
ええいっ
Excuse me!  I'm not Julia.
（ジュリアス）失礼ね
ジュリアじゃないわ
ジュリアス　ジュリアスよ
Ju-li-US!  I'm Julius!
Oh, I see...
あ そう
Hey, you're my type.
あんた 結構タイプよ
今夜 付き合う？
Wanna hang out with me tonight?
えっ 悪いけど先約があるんだ
I'm sorry, I already have plans.
あっ そうだ
グレンなら何か知ってるかも
Oh, yeah.  Gren might know something...
I've seen him with a woman before.
前に女と一緒だったのを
見たことがあるわ
グレン？
Gren?
It's cold.
（男娼１）おお 寒い
Looks like this is it for tonight.
（男娼２）今日は もう駄目ね
Oh, a customer?
あら お客？
Not even.  Can't you tell he's straight?
（ジュリアス）違うわよ
どう見てもノンケでしょ
Come on, let's switch locations.
さ 場所を変えましょ
Hey, who and where is Gren?
（スパイク）おおい
グレンってのは どこの誰だ？
So you wanna hang out with me tonight?
今夜 付き合う？
ブルークローのサックス吹きよ
んー ちゅっ
He's a sax player in Blue Crow.
はっくっしゅん へーくしゅん
はーっくしゅん
Take care.
（グレン）お大事に
That was close.
危ないところだった
３回くしゃみをして―
When someone sneezes and doesn't get told...
お大事にって言われないと
妖精になるんだ
...to take care, that person becomes a fairy.
この辺りの言い伝えさ
That's what they say around here.
Then it's okay.
ならないわよ
だって もう妖精だもの
I'm already a fairy.
I'm not as easy as I appear to be.
私は見た目ほど
軽い女じゃないわ
あいにく女には興味がなくて
Unfortunately, I am not interested in women...
Oh, that's a shame...
（フェイ）あら 残念
But the others seem to be highly interested.
でも 他の連中は
興味津々みたいだよ
You didn't know that there were no women in this town?
この町に女がいないこと
知らなかった？
（フェイ）ふーん
じゃあ モテモテだ
So I'll be very popular...
気をつけたほうが
You should watch out...
Thanks for the warning.
（フェイ）ご忠告 ありがと
I'm searching for something...
（スパイク）ちょっと
捜しものが あんだけど
ここには何もない
There's nothing here.
あるのは かびたパンと
動かない車と―
The only things are stale bread, a broken-down car, and rancid booze.
発酵しすぎた酒くらいだ
I'm looking for a guy named Gren.
グレンって男を捜してる
No idea.
（男）知らんな
I see.
そうか
Hey, you need something?
（スパイク）よう なんか用か？
You're Vicious, right?
ビシャスだな？
ME?!
俺が？
Where's the money?
金は どこだ？
If ya don't put out, it won't do ya any good!
（武装男）おとなしく出さねえと
ためになんねえぜ
This is annoying...
不愉快だ　猛烈に不愉快だ！
So annoying it's repulsive!
What the hell do you mean?!
どういうことなんだ？
Why the hell do you think I'm Vicious?
なんで俺がビシャスなんだ？
レ レッド･アイの取引があるって
情報が流れてる　うっ
There was info that there was gonna be some deal for Red-Eye.
From Gren to Vicious.
グレンからビシャスへってな
その金をいただこうと思ってよ
I thought of taking that cash...
俺が金 持ってるように
見えるかよ
You think I look like I got money?
よそもんは みんな金持ちさ
Foreigners are all rich.
コードネームジュリアか
And the code name was Julia?
（男）
へっ　いかにも尻軽女の名前だぜ
Heh, sure sounds like some easy wench's name!
Yeah, really.
ああ 全くだ
（パンチ）太陽系31万の
賞金稼ぎのみんな
稼いでるかい？
（ジェット）カウボーイだ
Gimme a Cowboy.
（ジュディ）
おなじみ
ビッグショットの時間よ
（ジュディ）
おなじみ
ビッグショットの時間よ
There are no bounties around here.
ここには賞金首なんざ いねえよ
（ジュディ）
おなじみ
ビッグショットの時間よ
ここには賞金首なんざ いねえよ
Bourbon with milk.
バーボンのミルク割りだ
はっは そっちのカウボーイか
Oh, THAT kind of Cowboy.  I knew that.  You can't possibly be a bounty-hunter.
分かってるさ
賞金稼ぎなわけねえよな
So, who's our customer today?
（ジュディ）
さて 今日のお客さんは
グレンシア･マルス･エリア･
郭･エッケナー？
Grencia Mars Elijah Guo Eckener.
長い名前
That's a long name!
Yeah.  He escaped from military prison three years ago...
（パンチ）そう ３年前に
軍事刑務所から脱獄した彼が
...and the statute of limitations is about to expire.
もうすぐ時効になっちまう
（ジュディ）てことは？
...and that means?
賞金が２倍にアップだ！
The bounty is double!
見逃せないチャンスね
This is a chance you can't miss!
But I kinda feel like we can let him go...
でも あたし ちょっと
見逃しちゃってもいいかなって気分
Judy, what are you saying?
ああ ジュディ なんてことを！
こいつは脱獄犯だよ
He's an escaped convict!
だってパンチ 彼ってば
とっても すてきなのよ
But Punch...
He's very handsome!
Just look at his picture!
見て！ この写真
Lesse...  Oh, come on...
（パンチ）どれどれ　なんだ
I'm much more handsome than he is.
これなら俺のほうが
よっぽど すてきだろう？
Punch, I just can't laugh at that joke.
（ジュディ）パンチ そのジョーク
全然 笑えないわ
おい あんなのは消してくれ
Hey, can you turn that thing off?!
Well, calm down.
ハハ 落ち着けよ　悪かったよ
I'm sorry, man.
Don't worry.  That guy passed out over there is a cop.
心配いらねえ
あそこで つぶれてるのが
お巡りだからな
何が言いたい？
What are you trying to say?
実は俺も賞金が懸けられてんだよ
Actually, there's a bounty on my head, too.
ここは そういうやつらの
吹きだまりさ
This place is a hideout for people like that.
なるほど
I see...
So you can rest assured.
だから安心していいぜ
Me?
俺？
What's with this?
（フェイ）何よ
I wanted to get rid of all this frustration, and nobody's coming?
せっかく憂さ晴らししたかったのに
誰も来ないじゃない
Oh, you're all here.
あら いたのね
お嬢さん その格好は目の毒だ
それとも誘ってんのかい？
Miss, your appearance is rather harmful to the eyes.
Or are you enticing us?
フフ そうなのよ
Yeah, I am.
Hold on a minute.
ちょっと待っててね
これ やんないと
爪が折れちゃうのよね フフ
If I don't do this, I'll chip a nail.
Okay, any time now!
さあ いつでもおいで
You wench!
（武装男）このアマ！ うっ
Hurry!
早く！
Why did you bring me here?
（フェイ）どうして連れてきたの？
Because you said you're a fairy.
（グレン）妖精だって言うから
Why did you come with me?
どうして ついてきた？
Because I've got no place to stay.
（フェイ）宿無しだから
You can trust me that easily?
（グレン）
簡単に信用していいのか？
You said you weren't interested in women.
（フェイ）女に興味ないんでしょ？
I might take your money and kill you...
（グレン）金を奪って殺すかも
That's fine.
（フェイ）いいわよ
私って見た目より長生きしてんの
I've lived longer than I seem.
壊れてるんだ
It's broken.
You came to such a slummy neighborhood all by yourself?
１人でこんな治安の悪い町に
来たのか？
I'm alone.
（フェイ）１人よ
I don't want comrades...
仲間なんていらないし
そんなの持つもんじゃないしね
...and it's not worth having any.
I end up worrying about things I don't have to...
余計な気 使っちゃうし
...you know, because I'm such a good woman.
ほら 私って いい女だからさ
男どもで
取り合いになっちゃうんだよね
All the guys end up fighting for me.
They often say that humans can't live alone...
人間 １人じゃ生きられないなんて
よく言うけど―
...but you can live pretty long by yourself.
結構 生きてけるもんなのよね
Instead of feeling alone in a group...
人の中で
独りぼっちだって感じるより―
...it's better to be alone in your solitude.
１人っきりで
孤独を感じるほうがマシ
When I'm dealing with them, it's nothing but trouble...
あいつらと関わってると
面倒ばっか増えて―
...and I don't get squat out of it...
なあんにもメリットなくって―
...so it doesn't matter if I'm there or not.
どうせ いてもいなくても…
フフッ
You just got scared of losing them.
離れるのが怖くなったんだね
その人たちと
だから先に離れちゃったんだ
So you distanced yourself from them.
You're weird.
（フェイ）変な人ね
Think so?
そう？
I don't know why I'm talking to you about this...
（フェイ）なあんで こんなこと
しゃべってんのか 分かんないわ
なあんか ざんげ室にいるみたい
あんた 牧師の経験ある？
I feel like I'm in a confessional.
Have you ever had experience as a minister?
No.
いや
くしゅん はっくしゅ
はっくしゅん
Take care.
お大事に
You want to take a shower?
（グレン）シャワーでも浴びる？
No thanks.
（フェイ）結構よ
I don't know where peeping toms might be.
どこから のぞかれるか
分かんないもの
You shouldn't peek, either.
君も のぞかないでくれよ
ふふん それは保証できないけど
Hm, I can't guarantee that.
Gren...  You're not there?
（ビシャス）グレン いないのか？
Vicious?!
ビシャス！
I'm out with 'honroutou'.
（ビシャス）
上がり役はホンロウトウ
満貫と裏ドラで３万2000だ
Along with the 'mangan' and the 'ura-dora', it's 32000.  I'll be waiting.
待っているぞ
Are you dating Julia behind my back?
（スパイク）
俺に内緒でジュリアとデートか？
Sir Spike!
（リン）スパイク様
Hey, Lin.  You've gotten pretty big.
（スパイク）
リンか　でかくなったな
（ビシャス）
昔は お前の弟分だったが今は違う
He used to work under you, but things are different now.
汚ねえ取引に名前を使われちゃあ
あいつも かわいそうだ
I feel sorry for her.  Having her name used for some crooked deal like this.
抜け駆けは お前の専門だったな
You were always the one leaving others out of the loop.
この間の決着が まだだぜ
We still haven't settled the score from earlier.
いつでも
Any time.
Lin!
（スパイク）リン！
Get out of the way, Lin!
（スパイク）どけ！ リン
ジュリアは いた　この町に
Julia was here, in this town.
Hey, out of the way, Lin!
おい どけ！ リン
リン…
Lin...
んはっ！
A woman?
女
あっ うあ どっちなのよ？
W-Which are you?
どっちでもあるし どっちでもない
I am both, but I am neither.
Too much time has passed by...
Aishiteta to nageku niwa
...to lament that we were deeply in love.
Amarinimo toki wa sugite shimatta
The wind keeps blowing, while my heart...
Mada kokoro no hokorobi wo
...cannot heal all the tears in it.
lyasenu mama kaze ga fuiteru
Someone, cry for me with parched eyes.
Kawaita hitomi de dareka naite kure
The real folk blues.
The real folk blues
I only want to know what true sadness is.
Honto no kanashimi ga shiritai dake
Sitting in muddy water...
Doro no kawa ni tsukatta
...isn't such a bad life...
Jinsei mo waruku wa nai
...if it ends after the first time...
Ichido kiri de owaru nara
～
Hey, how are men and women different?
（スパイク）
なあ 男と女って どう違うのかな？
Hmm...  I think women are hiding more vital things than men are.
（フェイ）
うーん 女は男より肝心なものを
隠してるって気がするけど
Yeah, but there are women that aren't feminine.
（スパイク）
ふーん でも女らしくない
女ってのもいるよな
And there are men that aren't masculine.
（フェイ）
男らしくない男もいるわ
What about those that aren't normally feminine...
（スパイク）
普段は女らしくないのに
ふとした瞬間―
...but show that side on some chance circumstance?
女っぽさが見えるってのが
俺は好きだな
I like that.
Oh?
（フェイ）あら
I'm not talking about you.
（スパイク）
お前のことじゃないからな
Then who?
（フェイ）じゃ 誰？
Maybe it's Ed!
（エド）エドかなあ？ エヘヘヘ
（スパイク）次回
「ジュピター･ジャズ（後編）」
Next episode: Jupiter Jazz, Part 2.
Maybe it's me.
（ジェット）俺かな？